Preliminary Guide to the Human Services Department records, 1960-1985 RG0094
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Human Services Department records
1960-1985
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Undergraduate Program in Human Services
RG0094
15 Linear Feet 10 record cartons
Materials in this collection include labor relations, training programs, grievance reports and transcripts, and articles on personnel/employee relations, training, and psychology from various journals. The collection covers the years 1960 to 1985.
Restrictions on Access
Series 1 is closed to research for 25 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Acquisitions data for this collection is unknown.
Historical or Biographical Note
In 1987 the School of Education was organized into four departments: Department of Teacher Preparation and Special Education; the Department of Human Kinetics and Tourism; the Department of Educational Leadership, and the Department of Human Services. Each is headed by a department chair. Since 1994 the School has been known as The Graduate School of Education and Human Development, when it transitioned from a comprehensive undergraduate/graduate entity to one focusing exclusively on graduate education. In 2004 the School celebrated its Centenary. The Dean of the School reports to the Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs. N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include labor relations, training programs, grievance reports and transcripts, and articles on personnel/employee relations, training, and psychology from various journals. The collection covers the years 1960 to 1985.
Formerly RG 8.6.1
Collection Organization
Organized into two series: Labor relations, training programs, grievance reports, and transcripts; and Articles.
Employee relations; Training; Foggy Bottom (Washington, D.C.); Psychology; Washington (D.C.); George Washington University. Graduate School of Education and Human Development; George Washington University; George Washington University. Human Services Dept.
- Labor relations, training programs, grievance reports, and transcripts, 1967-1985; RG0094 Series 1; 4.5 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  This series contains materials on labor relations, training programs, grievance reports, and transcripts from 1967 to 1985.
  Formerly ACC#29
  - Correspondence, 1975-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - OP: Employee Relation Functions, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - OP: Employee Relation: Old Budgets, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - OP: Projects Dress Code Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - OP: Project 1 Grievance Request: Policy, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - OP: Project 11 Grievance Request: Policy, 1983-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - A1/E/Employee Relations Activity Report: GWU Grievance Statistics, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - OP: Reports: ER Activity, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Employee Relations Activity Reports, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Involuntary Termination Reports, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Exit Interview Reports, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Nursing Exit Interview Reports and Correspondence, 1979-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - OP: Recordings, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - OP: Recordings, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - OP: Recordings, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - OP: Recordings, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - LOG: 1st Quarter, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - LOG: 2nd Quarter, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - LOG: 3rd Quarter, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - LOG: 4th Quarter, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - OP: Involuntary Termination, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - OP: Involuntary Termination, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Labor Relations Negotiations: Past Union Contracts, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Labor Relations Negotiations: Local Contracts, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    General note
    1467-08-73
  - Labor Relations Negotiations: 639 NEG, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Labor Relations Negotiations: Local Teamsters 639, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Labor Relations Negotiations: Local Teamsters 639, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Negotiating Material
  - Labor Relations Negotiations: Local Planning Committee, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Labor Relations, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Negotiators, Local, and GWU/Union Contract
  - OP: Coordination: Sexual Harassment Committee, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - OP: Coordination: EEA, \1 ca.1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - OP: Coordination: EEA, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - History of Training: DIWE Proposal, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - OP: Trainig Programs BASE, 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - OP: Training Programs: Union Prevention, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - OP: Training Programs: Executive Development Proposed, 06/1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - History of SDEL Training: Gelman Library Workshop Materials [1/2], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - History of SDEL Training: Gelman Library Workshop Materials [2/2], 1981 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - History of Training: SOS, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - SOS Participant Lists, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - OP: Employee Relations Grievance: Historical Information, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    General
  - Formal Grievance Reports, 1973-1980 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Grievance Request: Formal Grievance Hearing Committee Decisions, 1973-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Grievance Request: Formal Grievance Hearing Committee Decisions, 1977-1980 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Grievance Request: Formal Grievance Hearing committee Decisions, 1981-1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Grievance Reports, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Grievance Request: Informal Grievance Hearing Requests, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Grievance Request: Informal Grievance Hearing Requests, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Grievance Request: Informal Grievance Hearing Requests, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Grievance Request: Informal Grievance Hearing Requests, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Grievance Request: Informal Grievance Hearing Requests, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Grievance Request: Informal Grievance Hearing Requests, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Grievance Request: Informal Grievance Hearing, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Gilford, 02/07/1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    2 Tapes
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Baytop, 06/14/1983 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    4 Tapes
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Leath, 06/16/1983 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Grant, 07/07/1983 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Theola Myokhin, 10/03/1983 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Graves, 10/11/1983 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    1 Tape
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Deborah Winefield, 10/18/1983 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Veronica Foxx, 11/18/1983 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    3 Tapes
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Mr. Itarry White, 11/22/1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Roland Sims, 10/30/1983 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Jarvis Crocker, 03/27/1984 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Richard Giacomin, 04/12/1984 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Harlan Green, 04/25/1984 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Adrienne Scott, 03/23/1984 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Maurita Williams, 06/11/1984 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Alan Taylor, 06/29/1984 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Christine Richardson, 07/23/1984 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Beverly Myers, 07/30/1984 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Lucille Washington, 08/21/1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Gail Hunter, 02/28/1984 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Ronnie Hynes, 10/17/1984 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: James Belteau, 11/02/1984 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Rybicke, 03/06/1985 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Sharon Littlejohn, 04/13/1985 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Denise Moore, 07/02/1985 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Rufus Kearns, 07/16/1985 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Abdullah Azim, 11/22/1985 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Allis Harrison, 12/10/1985 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Formal Grievance Hearing Audio Transcripts: Leslie Thornton, 12/19/1985 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Tape Conversation between Charles Lease and Jackie Grant, 06/18/1981 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Chronology of Labor History, ND; Series 1
  - Teaching Labor Studies in the Schools, Lesson Plans, 1987; Series 1
  - Teaching Labor STudies in the Schools, Lesson Plans, Volume 2, 1988; Series 1
- Articles, 1960-1985; RG0094 Series 2; 10.5 Linear feet
  This series contains articles on personnel/employee relations, training, and psychology from different journals.
  Formerly ACC#163, 175
  This series has a paper container list in the reading room, please ask staff for assistance.